<emails>
	<email title="Research Meeting">
		<received date="15/05/18" time="10:32" />
		<from>matt.gloam@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi Roger,
The meeting has been moved to next Tuesday (22nd), see you next week!
Matt.</body>
	</email>
	<email title="SWIPE ACCESS TO FREEMAN BUILDING">
		<received date="15/05/18" time="11:02" />
		<from>lottie.cairns@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>students@usoo.ac.uk; staff@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Dear Colleagues

I have contacted Campus Services re the card reader into Freeman Building which is now active during standard office hours. I have been informed that at the request of Security, free-flow and student access to Freeman has been removed for the duration of the exhibition. This includes the routes to Freeman from Pathman; normal access will resume from 28th May 2018.

Regards,
Lottie</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Half-day seminar on Innovation Education for Sustainable Development">
		<received date="15/05/18" time="07:42" />
		<from>zakir.emery@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>staff@usoo.ac.uk; compulab@usoo.ac.uk; centreforinternationaldevelopment@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Good morning! A final reminder that we are hosting a half-day seminar today (Monday) on Innovation Education for Sustainable Development If you can spare the time, it would lovely to see you there! Coffees and Teas will be served from 9.00 am and we will start the ball rolling at 9.30am, finishing at 12.30pm. 
 
Innovation Education for Sustainable Development
Tuesday May 15th 9.00-12.30pm
University Campus
Design Building, DS04, Presentation Hall
 
Dear all, 
I am hosting research collaborators from Myanmar and Dr Tessa Sandoval from Australia and will be running a half-day seminar on the theme of Innovation Education for Sustainable Development. This activity is part of a research network that I co-founded with Tessa – Design and Social Innovation in Asia-Pacific (DESIAP) to connect practitioners, researchers and communities working in the Social Innovation space in Asia-Pacific. Many of our current work are focused on using co-design approaches to enhance and support education activities in the context of sustainable development. This visit is supported through the university’s Global Challenges Research Fund strategy to encourage and support research with countries receiving Official Development Assistance (ODA).
 
Point B Design and Training is a DESIAP member and collaborator based in Myanmar. They have a strong track record in delivering training programmes on 21st Century Skills to rebuild education systems and community governance in Myanmar. They were established in 2012 using Human-centred design approach to support new ideas, tools and processes for humanitarian development in low-income communities.
 
The seminar will feature presentations by Point B, Tessa Sandoval and a number of researchers across the University involved in Education, Design and Development such as Professor Hailey Dunlap, Professor Sonya Gordon and Dr Lilly Oliver. Some of the themes talked about will be around informal education, education and technology, intergenerational community learning, youth transitions and 21st century skills for development.  
 
The seminar is open to anyone (academic or researchers on projects) and PGRs across the University. We also welcome external visitors – so please do forward it on to anyone who you feel will be interested. 
 
If you’d like to participate – please register. It will also help in anticipating interested numbers, so I can book the appropriate room size.
 
Best wishes,
Zakir</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Assessment Question">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="20:35" />
		<from>maximus.whitehead@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi Roger,
Which room is the assessment in on Friday 11am, we are unsure if it is in DS04 or DS09 this time.
Thanks,
Max</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Automatic Reply: Room Booking">
		<received date="13/05/18" time="14:06" />
		<from>booking@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>The room Dunlop Building DS09 has been booked for the time 11:00 to 13:00 on 18/05/18.

DO NOT REPLY TO THIS EMAIL.
</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Shut up & write session Tuesday - 10am">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="12:16" />
		<from>humza.burnett@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi everyone,
I know it’s full marking time, but just to let you know I’ve booked the FR104 meeting room again for this Tuesday at 10am if anyone is interested in some ‘Shut up & write’ time.
I’m going to try and do this every other week, so mark it in your calendars if you are interested and just come along when you can.

Humza</body>
	</email>
	<email title="VR Conference tickets on sale soon">
		<received date="12/05/18" time="10:32" />
		<from>tickets@vrconf.org</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi Roger,
Tickets for the conference go on sale 15/05/18 at 12pm. Reply to this email after then to reserve yours but act fast as only limited places are available.
See you there,
VR Conference Organisers
</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Blackboard Upgrade – Reinstall the Mobile App">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="16:43" />
		<from>it.helpline@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>it.customer-service@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Blackboard Ultra has launched and you can login once again to access and submit work.  An important part of the upgrade was to improve the security around Blackboard so that you’re comfortable using the service and staying safe.  

To continue using the Blackboard Mobile App, you will need to ‘reset the app’ so that it picks up the new settings.  We’ve provided full steps below for your device:

Android Users
1	Go to Settings > Application Manager > Choose 'Blackboard' or 'Instructor'
•	On Android 5.x and previous: Choose Clear Data
•	On Android 6.x: Choose Storage then Clear Data
2	Delete the App
3	Reinstall the App from the Google Play Store.
Apple Users
1	Delete the Blackboard App – confirming that you want to delete its data
2	Reinstall from the App Store.

IT Support - open 24 hours, 365 days a year 
Email	it.helpline@usoo.ac.uk

Chat	usoo.ac.uk/itchat</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Automatic reply: Ethics Form 36754">
		<received date="08/05/18" time="15:23" />
		<from>walid.couch@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>I am engaged in research fieldwork at the moment and am unlikely to respond to messages before the end of May.
Research students should note the arrangements we have made.
If you a student requiring a response before this please re-direct your enquiry to ee.ask4help@usoo.ac.uk 
If your enquiry is a Freedom of Information request, please re-direct your enquiry to: us.foi@usoo.ac.uk 
</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Lego">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="11:31" />
		<from>ayda.massey@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi everyone, does anyone have Lego blocks I could borrow for my workshop this week? 

Thanks 
Ayda
</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Scholar AI Metrics">
		<received date="11/05/18" time="09:22" />
		<from>krish.ayers@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi,

It’s all just numbers but Scholar just released their metrics for the top venues/journals for each field.

The AI ones are here: https://scholar.google.com/citations?view_op=top_venues&hl=en&vq=eng_artificialintelligence 

(Psssstttt… it’s still NIPS).

Sadly I’m struggling to find ‘design’ as a subcategory…

Cheers,
Krish</body>
	</email>
	<email title="VRST 2018 CALL FOR PAPERS">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="13:44" />
		<from>yoshimoto@IEEE.ORG</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>VRST 2018 CALL FOR PAPERS
https://vrst.acm.org/vrst2018/
The ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology (VRST) is the premier international symposium for the presentation of new research results, systems, and techniques among researchers and developers concerned with augmented, virtual and mixed reality
(AR/VR/MR, XR for short) software and technology.
VRST brings together the main international research groups working on XR, along with many of the world’s leading companies that provide or utilize XR systems. VRST 2018 will be held in Tokyo, Japan, hosted by Waseda University, from Wednesday, Nov. 28th to Saturday, Dec. 1st, 2018. The event is sponsored by ACM SIGCHI and SIGGRAPH.

VRST 2018 welcomes submissions of research papers that relate (but not limited) to topics given below.
- XR technology and devices
- Advanced display technologies and immersive projection technologies
- Low-latency and high-performance XR
- Multi-user and distributed XR
- XR software infrastructures
- XR authoring systems
- HCI for XR
- Real-time techniques for XR
- Haptics, smell and taste
- Computer graphics techniques for XR
- Computer vision techniques for XR
- Modeling and simulation
- AI approaches for XR
- XR applications

Submissions in other related areas are also welcome. See the symposium website for more details: https://vrst.acm.org/vrst2018

Authors are invited to submit papers of no more than 10 pages for full papers and 4 pages for short papers, both with 2-column "teaser" figures on the first page. All submissions must be in English. All accepted papers will be published in the Symposium Proceedings and will be included in the ACM Digital Library (EI-indexed). Papers and poster abstracts should be prepared using the "sigconf" ACM template style. ACM article templates (LaTeX and Word) are available from: http://www.acm.org/publications/proceedings-template
VRST uses a double-blind review process. Therefore, submissions and supporting materials (e.g., videos) should not contain information (including citations) that unnecessarily identifies the authors or their institutions or places of work. All submissions must be made electronically as PDF files. Authors are encouraged to submit videos to aid the program committee in the review of their submissions, but should make sure all necessary codecs are included.
Extended versions of two or three best papers from VRST 2018 will be invited to resubmit to IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.
We also invite submissions of Poster and Demo papers (2 pages). We particularly encourage industrial researchers, startups, and researchers early in their careers to submit. Accepted Poster and Demo papers will be published in the Symposium Proceedings and will be included in the ACM Digital Library.

Papers, posters, and demos must be submitted through the online submission site:
https://new.precisionconference.com/~sigchi

Details about the submission procedure can be found on the symposium website:
https://vrst.acm.org/vrst2018/submissions.html

Important Dates
- May 30, 2018, 23:59 PST   Papers with all material submission deadline
- June 1, 2018, 23:59 PST   Posters and demos submission deadline
- June 25, 2018   Author notification papers, posters and demos
- July 1, 2018   Camera-ready papers due
- November 28 - December 1, 2018   Conference in Tokyo, Japan</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Compensating Participants with Donations to Charity?">
		<received date="12/05/18" time="10:51" />
		<from>krish.ayers@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi,

Quick query, does anyone have experience at Northumbria of compensating their participants with donations to charity rather than shopping vouchers?

John and I are running a study (related to charitable giving) where we would like to give the option to donate to a charity of their choice. I just wondered if there were any potential issues with this, or whether with a receipt from the donation it could be easily claimed back as expenses?

Cheers,
Krish</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Off-Campus Workshop Venues?">
		<received date="09/05/18" time="15:58" />
		<from>colin.galloway@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi all,

do some of you have experience with / knowledge about off-campus venues (preferably near city-centre) that are open for hosting workshops - for free? I understand that we can book on-campus locations, but am considering alternative solutions.

Contact me if you have any leads!

Best,
Colin</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Alibaba Cloud UK Business Development Manager is visiting Freeman on 5th June">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="17:02" />
		<from>vivien.buck@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Dear All,

I am very pleased to let you know that the business development manager Asad Knights is planning to visit our department to seek any potential project collaboration 2-4pm on 5th June. For those who might not know Alibaba Cloud, Alibaba Cloud is a business unit of Alibaba Group, the largest e-commerce platform in China. Similar to Amazon, Alibaba is developing their cloud computing services and solutions for organizations. Please find an introduction to Alibaba cloud as attached. 

You are cordially invited to attend the talk from Alibaba Cloud 2-4pm on 5th June. 

Please reply this email by voting yes/no so that I can send the invitation to you through the calendar. 

Regards,
Vivien</body>
	</email>
	<email title="RE: PREDICT Conference">
		<received date="14/05/18" time="19:12" />
		<from>omer.knott@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to> compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi all,
Just returning from the EFSA 2018 Conference and I happened to meet Cronan McNamara, who is one of the main organizers of the PREDICT Conference to be held in Dublin from Oct. 2. 
It’s highly possible most of you are already aware of this one, and if so, apologies. Heard good things about this event from people, so thought it’d be good to pass along. They have discounted rates for academics and students, so do forward to those who might be interested. Here’s the link: https://www.predictconference.com/ 
Cheers,
Omer</body>
	</email>
	<email title="VR & AR in automotive customer engagement and sales">
		<received date="11/05/18" time="15:19" />
		<from>dmclean@ vr-intelligence.com</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi Roger,
The automotive industry has used immersive technology for design reviews and testing for decades. But in recent years, its use has extended beyond the workshop to the showroom, where virtual reality gives consumers an entirely new way to make a purchasing decision.
To explore the progress in this area, VR Intelligence has teamed up with ZeroLight - market leaders in VR retail experiences in the automotive industry - to produce a report analysing brand new data on customer perceptions in automotive retail VR.
Get the free report on the how automotive brands are using VR & AR to sell to customers here
The report includes customer survey results as well as case studies and interviews with three of the world’s leading pioneers in this area:
-	Marcus Kuehne, Strategy Lead for Immersive Technologies, Audi
-	Damien Mauric, VP of Business Development, StarVR 
-	Florian Stiller, Head of Event and Sport Marketing for Central and South-Eastern Europe, BMW Group 
To see the full report, including market research analysis, case studies and interviews, head here.
Any questions, or feedback – let me know.
Thanks,
Daryl</body>
	</email>
	<email title="VR/AR Market State">
		<received date="11/05/18" time="15:19" />
		<from>aamir.zuniga@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Hi Roger,
I am not sure how much you care for the commercial side of VR/AR, but here’s a summary article about what it is used for commercially: https://www.hometoys.com/article/2018/09/before-the-game-the-real-market-for-vrar-right-now/38765/
I hope it’s useful to you.
Best regards,
Aamir</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Magic leap video on BBC">
		<received date="05/05/18" time="13:02" />
		<from>ronald.mcdaniel@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk, r.k.adams@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>I found this helpful for understanding what you’re both on about - https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/technology-45521497/a-new-reality-putting-magic-leap-one-to-the-test - it shows email checking and talks a bit about workplace AR</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Unfiltered.news">
		<received date="05/05/18" time="18:15" />
		<from>aamir.zuniga@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>compulab@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>I haven’t heard anyone mentioning this source in relation to social media, activism or anything related, so here it is:
https://unfiltered.news
This is Google-based system that allows you to see which news are reported on less in a given country compared to the global averages.
Best regards,
Aamir</body>
	</email>
	<email title="Research and Innovation Services financial schemes to support students">
		<received date="10/05/18" time="14:12" />
		<from>researchsupport@usoo.ac.uk</from>
		<to>researchsupport@usoo.ac.uk</to>
		<body>Dear postgraduate research students/supervisors
This year we have had an unprecedented amount of applications to our three financial schemes:
•         Conference Bursary Scheme
•         Events Support Scheme
•         Impact Scheme
Students have applied and been successful in travelling all over the world to present their research findings at conferences, organising and delivering events on-campus and organising events that demonstrate the impact of their research.
Our schemes have now CLOSED for this academic year, no new applications can now be accepted or approved.  All outstanding applications are currently being considered and students will receive the outcomes of these in the next few days.
We will be spending the summer months reviewing our three schemes, and will be open for new applications for the 2018/19 academic year in August.
Kind regards
Research and Innovation Services</body>
	</email>
  <email title="VR/AR Expert Interviews: Unity, Volvo and Forbes Inside">
    <received date="12/05/18" time="14:51" />
    <from>aparkinson@vr-int.com</from>
    <to>roger.flass@usoo.ac.uk</to>
    <body>Hi Roger,
      Over the next 12 months, XR's potential across enterprise is huge. To unlock the full potential of the immersive transformation, companies must discover the right solutions, provide metrics to track success and, critically, show how XR will improve their business outcomes.

      Reuters Events caught up with some of the key decision makers speaking at this year’s XR Immersive Enterprise: Global Online Edition (May 5-7, Eastern time) to find out where they see the greatest enterprise potential, how they are getting there, and to get a taste of what they’ll be discussing at the global online summit in July.

      Get access to the exclusive Q&As here

      Unity, Volvo and Forbes are joining 50+ expert speakers to share their experiences and insights in May:

      “Today every enterprise company in the world uses VR, AR and MR… We see XR being used in automotive for design and manufacturing, reducing error, speeding up iteration time, and all the way through the customer journey to visualization and point of sale.” – Unity Technologies

      “XR is an opportunity for me, a platform to deliver through a more current medium that is more engaging than other digital delivery options in the past.” – Volvo

      “Enterprise XR is hitting an inflection point and the foundational pieces are falling into place.” – Forbes

      Check out the full responses from Rolls-Royce, Aggreko, Biogen and more here

      All the best,
      Asha</body>
  </email>
  <email title="VRWOO Cluster meeting (AR/VR/XR)">
    <received date="14/05/18" time="10:59" />
    <from>terence@vrwoo.org.uk</from>
    <to>everyoneonlist@vrwoo.org.uk</to>
    <body>Hi everyone

      I hope I find you all well.

      I would like to invite you to a VRTGO cluster meeting at 2pm on Wednesday the 29th (that’s next week).

      As the new cluster manager I haven’t had the opportunity to meet with many of you, so this will be an opportunity to get to get together and put some faces to names and hopefully get an understanding of what you are all up to. We will be discussing all thing Virtual/Augmented reality, what’s going on in the sector, what may be coming at us and hopefully some upcoming opportunities. The key aim of the cluster is to promote the region as having expertise and facilities that can produce world class content in everything XR. So the more I know about you, the more I can share and the more opportunities we can attract.

      I’m in discussions with a couple of speakers and hope to be able to confirm something soon. We will keep things very informal on this occasion.

      Regards
      Terence Hassan</body>
  </email>
</emails>